<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entries>
<Entry id="Subtitle" prefix="">
  <English>Making Links.</English>
  <Deutsch>Werte verändern.</Deutsch>
  <Russian>Как соединять nodes.</Russian>
</Entry>

<Entry id="0" prefix="">
  <English>
Oh, there are some links missing in this patch.
You see the SpiralSpread node, which creates a list of 200 points that are then supplied to the Point node (via a Multiply node) to draw them. Let's rotate the spiral.
  </English>
  <Deutsch></Deutsch>
  <Russian></Russian>
</Entry>

<Entry id="1" prefix="">
  <English>
Start a link with a left click on the 'Output' pin of the LFO node. Do not drag, just click on the pin and release the button, the link is started and follows the mouse now.

Note how most of the inputs on the Transform node are now bigger, indicating that they would accept the connection.

Hover the input pins of the Transform node with the mouse cursor to find the input labeled 'Rotate' and click on it to finish the link.
  </English>
  <Deutsch></Deutsch>
  <Russian></Russian>
</Entry>

<Entry id="2" prefix="">
  <English>
Now start a link with a left click on the 'Output' pin of the Transform node.

Note how the first input on the Multiply node has grown to show you it is willing to accept the link.

Finish the link with a left click on the that pin and you should see the spiral spin.
  </English>
  <Deutsch></Deutsch>
  <Russian></Russian>
</Entry>

<Entry id="3" prefix="">
  <English>
To remove a link, first select it by clicking it with the left mouse button. Then click it with the right mouse button or press the DEL key to delete it. 

Also while making a link you can always press the right mouse button to cancel the operation.
  </English>
  <Deutsch>
...
  </Deutsch>
  <Russian>
...
  </Russian>
</Entry>

<Entry id="4" prefix="">
  <English>
Explanation:
The LFO node returns a constantly changing value that goes from 0 to 1 and jumps back to 0 again...
  </English>
  <Deutsch></Deutsch>
  <Russian>
  ...
  </Russian>
</Entry>

<Entry id="5" prefix="">
  <English>
For more details on linking nodes, see:
  </English>
  <Deutsch></Deutsch>
  <Russian>
  ...
  </Russian>
</Entry>
</Entries>
