<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entries>
<Entry id="Subtitle" prefix="">
<English>
Adding IOBoxes to an existing patch. 

Don't worry if you don't understand the whole patch yet. In this tutorial we simply want you to learn how to add IOBoxes to an existing patch in order to control some of its parameters.

In the renderer you see a randomly moving pointcloud where dots whose distance is below a certain threshold are connected by a line. Let's see how we can manipulate the animation a bit..
</English>
<Deutsch>Werte verändern.</Deutsch>
<Russian>Как изменять значения.</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="1" prefix="">
<English>
On the &lt; node hover the second input called 'Input 2' to see there is already a value in that pin. In order to control that value via an IOBox click the input to start a link from it, then middle click (or press SPACE and right-click) to create an IOBox anywhere in the patch. Besides the IOBox there'll appear a list of options (Bang, Toggle, Press,...) which you can simply ignore for now. Move the mouse away a bit to get rid of it. 

Note that as you change this value more or less points will be connected.
</English>
<Deutsch></Deutsch>
<Russian>
Это Bang IOBox. Кликни правой кнопкой мышки внутри. В этот момент Counter посчитает вверх.
</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="2" prefix="">
<English>
To change the color of the lines between the dots hover the inputs of the Line node with the mouse and find the one labeled 'Color'. Again click that input to start a link and then middle-click anywhere in the patch to create a color IOBox.

Now let's change the width of the line. Find the 'Width' input on the Line node and create an IOBox as before but now note the popup with the options you get and choose 'Integer' to get an IOBox that lets you operate in whole values.

Change the value in this IOBox to get fatter lines.
</English>
<Deutsch></Deutsch>
<Russian>
Нажми правой кнопкой мышки в Value IOBox и держа кнопку нажатой поводи мышкой вверх-вниз, чтобы поменять значение. Это значение определяет количество точек, которые будут отрисованы.
</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="3" prefix="">
<English>
Finally let us change the shape of the points by finding the 'Type' input on the Point node and creating an IOBox as we just learned: Click the input and then middle-click anywhere in the patch to get an enumeration IOBox. Then rightclick the IOBox to choose between 'Rectangle, Triangle, Circle'.
</English>
<Deutsch>
Drücke die rechte Maustaste in der Auswahl-IOBox um eine andere Schriftart auszuwählen
</Deutsch>
<Russian>
Кликни правой кнопокой мышки в Enumeration IOBox, чтобы выбрать другой шрифт.
</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="4" prefix="">
<English>
This is again a Value IOBox. To set it to a particular value (instead of scrolling through the them) doubleclick the left mouse button inside it and type a number. This value defines how long it takes to animate between the points positions.
</English>
<Deutsch></Deutsch>
<Russian>
Это уже знакомый Value IOBox, чтобы задать конкретное значение (вместо того, чтобы скроллить через них) щелкните 2 раза левой кнопкой мышки и наберите нужное значение. Значение определяет как долго длится анимация между позициями точек.
</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="5" prefix="">
<English>
And this is the Color IOBox.
Press the right mouse button inside it and:
- move the mouse up-and-down to change the brightness
- hold the CTRL key pressed and move the mouse up-and-down to change the saturation
- move the mouse left-and-right to change the hue.
- hold the ALT key pressed and move up-and-down to change transparency (alpha)
</English>
<Deutsch></Deutsch>
<Russian>
А это Color IOBox.
Нажите и удерживайте правую кнопку мышки:
- движение вверх-вниз изменяет яркость цвета,
- клавиша CTRL и движение вверх-вниз изменяет насыщенность цвета,
- движение влево-вправо изменят тон.
</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="6" prefix="">
<English>
For more details on using IOBoxes see:
</English>
<Deutsch></Deutsch>
<Russian>
- Движение мышки при нажатой правой кнопке: скролл через значения IOBox.
- Клик правой кнокой мышки: щелкает, переключает или нажимает IOBox (мы еще рассмотрим эти варианты IOBox чуть позже)
- Клик правой кнопкой мышки при нажатой клавише ALT: сбрасывает значение IOBox до стандартного.
- Все эти правила также применимы и к pin.
</Russian>
</Entry>
</Entries>
