<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entries>
<Entry id="Subtitle" prefix="">
<English>Welcome to your first steps in vvvv. Before you learn to create your own patches, in this tutorial you learn how interact with existing patches. 

As you can see below, a patch consists of nodes (the gray boxes with text in them) and links (the black lines between them). Hover a node with the mouse to see a tooltip showing its full name. Hover the input and output pins (the dark little dots) of a node to see their names and current values. 

Follow the numbers and read the corresponding explanation on the right side to learn how to change some of the parameters that drive the animation in the renderer below.
</English>
<Deutsch>
Halo halo zu deinen ersten Schritten in vvvv. Bevor du lernst, deine eigenen patches zu bauen, zeigt dir dieses Tutorial wie man bei bestehnden patches Werte verändern kann.

Wie du unten siehst, besteht ein Patch aus Nodes (die grauen Boxen mit Text) und Links (die schwarzen Linien dazwischen). Wenn du mit der Maus über einen Node fährst, verrät dir ein Tooltip dessen ganzen Namen. Das gleiche gilt für die Input- und Output-Pins (die kleinen schwarzen Quadrate) von Nodes, die ihren Namen und ihren aktuellen Wert zeigen.

Folge jetzt den Nummern und lies die zugehörige Beschreibung auf der rechten Seite um zu verstehen, wie man die Werte hier im Patch verändern kann, welche die Animation im Renderer unten steuern.
</Deutsch>
<Russian>Как изменять значения.</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="1" prefix="">
<English>
This node is called a Bang IOBox. Here it is connected to the Reset input of the LFO node. If you rightclick the IOBox it will reset the LFO. 
</English>
<Deutsch></Deutsch>
<Russian>
Это Bang IOBox. Кликни правой кнопкой мышки внутри. В этот момент Counter посчитает вверх.
</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="2" prefix="">
<English>
Press and hold the right mouse button in the Value IOBox and drag the mouse up and down to change the value. This value defines how many points the TypoSpread node generates.
</English>
<Deutsch></Deutsch>
<Russian>
Нажми правой кнопкой мышки в Value IOBox и держа кнопку нажатой поводи мышкой вверх-вниз, чтобы поменять значение. Это значение определяет количество точек, которые будут отрисованы.
</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="3" prefix="">
<English>
Click the right mouse button in Enumeration IOBox to choose a different font.
</English>
<Deutsch>
Drücke die rechte Maustaste in der Auswahl-IOBox um eine andere Schriftart auszuwählen
</Deutsch>
<Russian>
Кликни правой кнопокой мышки в Enumeration IOBox, чтобы выбрать другой шрифт.
</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="4" prefix="">
<English>
This is again a Value IOBox. To set it to a particular value (instead of scrolling through the them) doubleclick the left mouse button inside it and type a number. This value defines how long it takes to animate between the points positions.
</English>
<Deutsch></Deutsch>
<Russian>
Это уже знакомый Value IOBox, чтобы задать конкретное значение (вместо того, чтобы скроллить через них) щелкните 2 раза левой кнопкой мышки и наберите нужное значение. Значение определяет как долго длится анимация между позициями точек.
</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="5" prefix="">
<English>
And this is the Color IOBox.
Press the right mouse button inside it and:
- move the mouse up-and-down to change the brightness
- hold the CTRL key pressed and move the mouse up-and-down to change the saturation
- move the mouse left-and-right to change the hue.
- hold the ALT key pressed and move up-and-down to change transparency (alpha)
</English>
<Deutsch></Deutsch>
<Russian>
А это Color IOBox.
Нажите и удерживайте правую кнопку мышки:
- движение вверх-вниз изменяет яркость цвета,
- клавиша CTRL и движение вверх-вниз изменяет насыщенность цвета,
- движение влево-вправо изменят тон.
</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="6" prefix="">
<English>
For more details on using IOBoxes, see:
</English>
<Deutsch></Deutsch>
<Russian>
- Движение мышки при нажатой правой кнопке: скролл через значения IOBox.
- Клик правой кнокой мышки: щелкает, переключает или нажимает IOBox (мы еще рассмотрим эти варианты IOBox чуть позже)
- Клик правой кнопкой мышки при нажатой клавише ALT: сбрасывает значение IOBox до стандартного.
- Все эти правила также применимы и к pin.
</Russian>
</Entry>
<Entry id="7" prefix="">
<English>
More Tutorials are available online:
</English>
<Deutsch></Deutsch>
<Russian>
- Движение мышки при нажатой правой кнопке: скролл через значения IOBox.
- Клик правой кнокой мышки: щелкает, переключает или нажимает IOBox (мы еще рассмотрим эти варианты IOBox чуть позже)
- Клик правой кнопкой мышки при нажатой клавише ALT: сбрасывает значение IOBox до стандартного.
- Все эти правила также применимы и к pin.
</Russian>
</Entry>

</Entries>
